<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Obsidian Mindmap]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Obsidian Mindmap</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:06:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:06:39 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[guiding principles]]></title><description><![CDATA[Behind every action, activity, there seems to be a guiding principle or process, even if we don't realize or cannot articulate them. But being aware can provide a powerful framework.Disclaimer: this 'list' will change massively as we go on, as the new things we learn and discover using these guiding principles will recursively change the process itself. The list here will have the TLDR version with more details in the full articles.As a first, self recursive guiding principle let's have:
<a data-href="Keep in mind, check and develop the guiding principles you have" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Keep in mind, check and develop the guiding principles you have</a>
We have used words, English words to articulate, note and document this first guiding principle. If the words make sense to you, good, it means we made an intelligible sentence. Words and writing are a very very powerful tool.
<br><a data-href="Inspect your base assumptions" href="guiding-principles/inspect-your-base-assumptions.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Inspect your base assumptions</a>
<br>We are not starting everything from 0, all the time. Whatever we do, whenever we communicate we make a number (innumerable) assumptions. This has an important function to keep things efficient, but there can be disadvantages, and in this case serious ones. But what exactly does the word, <a data-href="assumption" href="words/assumption.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">assumption</a> mean?
<br><a data-href="Study the meaning of the words" href="guiding-principles/study-the-meaning-of-the-words.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Study the meaning of the words</a>
A lot can be learned by reading the dictionary entry of a word. The Contexts it is used in, it's Relateds, Synonyms, etc., it's Etymology (origin) can reveal new aspects and insights that will make thinking and documentation more effective and precise.
<br><a data-href="Make the principles actionable" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Make the principles actionable</a>
They are useful as text, but they will come alive as code. For example:
To keep in mind the guiding principles, set up reminders and other mechanisms
similar for the base assumptions
create a template for words the words you use
Of course this has to be elaborated much more to become robust. But let's start by defining some words that we have used so far.<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="words/index" data-href="words/index" href="words/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">index</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="words/welcome" data-href="words/welcome" href="words/welcome.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">welcome</a><br>
<a data-href="guide" href="words/guide.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">guide</a><br>
<a data-href="assume" href="words/assume.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">assume</a><br>
<a data-href="assumption" href="words/assumption.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">assumption</a>]]></description><link>guiding-principles.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">guiding principles.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:05:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[assume]]></title><description><![CDATA[
verb suppose to be the case, without proof.
take or begin to have (power or responsibility).
begin to have (a specified quality, appearance, or extent).
take on or adopt (a manner or identity), sometimes falsely. late Middle English: from Latin assumere, from ad- ‘towards’ + sumere ‘take’.]]></description><link>words/assume.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">words/assume.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:05:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[assumption]]></title><description><![CDATA[
noun a thing that is accepted as true or as certain to happen, without proof.
the action of taking on power or responsibility. verb
Middle English (in assumption(sense 3 of the noun)): from Old French asompsion or Latin assumptio(n- ), from the verb assumere (see <a data-href="assume" href="words/assume.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">assume</a>)]]></description><link>words/assumption.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">words/assumption.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[welcome]]></title><description><![CDATA[
adjective Received with pleasure and hospitality into one's company or home.
Giving pleasure or satisfaction; agreeable or gratifying. noun A cordial greeting or hospitable reception given to an arriving person.
A reception upon arrival.
The state of being welcome. verb To greet, receive, or entertain (another or others) cordially or hospitably. interjection Used to greet cordially a visitor or recent arrival. Old English wilcuma ‘a person whose coming is pleasing’, wilcumian (verb), from wil- ‘desire, pleasure’ + cuman ‘come’. The first element was later changed to wel- ‘well’, influenced by Old French bien venu or Old Norse velkominn .Middle English, alteration (influenced by wel, well) of Old English wilcuma, welcome guest, welcome; see gwā- in Indo-European roots.]]></description><link>words/welcome.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">words/welcome.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 23:57:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[
noun Something that serves to guide, point out, or otherwise facilitate reference, especially.
An alphabetized list of names, places, and subjects treated in a printed work, giving the page or pages on which each item is mentioned. late Middle English: from Latin index, indic- ‘forefinger, informer, sign’, from in- ‘towards’ + a second element related to dicere ‘say’ or dicare ‘make known’; compare with indicate. The original sense ‘index finger’ (with which one points), came to mean ‘pointer’ (late 16th century), and figuratively something that serves to point to a fact or conclusion; hence a list of topics in a book (‘pointing’ to their location).Middle English, forefinger, from Latin; see deik- in Indo-European roots.From Latin index&nbsp;("a discoverer, informer, spy; of things, an indicator, the forefinger, a title, superscription"), from indicō&nbsp;("point out, show"); see indicate.]]></description><link>words/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">words/index.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 23:45:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is the main page, because every site needs one.<a data-href="welcome" href="welcome.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">welcome</a><br>
<a data-href="digital garden" href="digital-garden.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">digital garden</a><br>
<a data-href="inspirations" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">inspirations</a>]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 23:36:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[guide]]></title><description><![CDATA[
One who shows the way by leading, directing, or advising.
One who serves as a model for others, as in a course of conduct.
<a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://wordnik.com/words/guide" target="_self">https://wordnik.com/words/guide</a>]]></description><link>words/guide.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">words/guide.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 23:20:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Study the meaning of the words]]></title><description><![CDATA[Once we learn a language, we can use the words, the main building blocks of a sentence, effortlessly. But there is often much more to a word than what we know on the surface level.Human language is said to be 'messy' and ambiguous, context dependent, and not nearly as 'precise' as a formal language, like a programming language. The conversation with a friend, or this page will not crash if I make a semantic (meaning) or syntax (grammatical) error. Still, a lot can be learned by reading the dictionary entry of a word. A lot of words have their original roots in Latin and Greek.Studying these aspects of the words can provide new, useful insights, improve our mastery of them, etc.<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="http://www.wordnik.com" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="http://www.wordnik.com" target="_self">www.wordnik.com</a>]]></description><link>guiding-principles/study-the-meaning-of-the-words.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">guiding principles/Study the meaning of the words.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 23:16:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Inspect your base assumptions]]></title><link>guiding-principles/inspect-your-base-assumptions.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">guiding principles/Inspect your base assumptions.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:55:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[welcome]]></title><description><![CDATA[Welcome to my mind garden. It is in the form of a <a data-href="digital garden" href="digital-garden.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">digital garden</a>.<br>The goal is yet hard to define and put into words, so for now we will start with the <a data-href="guiding principles" href="guiding-principles.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">guiding principles</a>.]]></description><link>welcome.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">welcome.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:22:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[digital garden]]></title><description><![CDATA[I decided to try this form of publishing as it aligns the most with my way of thinking (at the moment).It's purpose is to use it as a means of documenting, publishing (sharing) my thinking about a couple of initiatives I am trying to realize.I hope it will help to force me to think very carefully about the ideas I am trying to develop, about the words I use, and the thoughts I publish.]]></description><link>digital-garden.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">digital garden.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:20:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[erudition]]></title><description><![CDATA[
noun Deep, extensive learning. synonym: knowledge.
Learning; scholarship; knowledge gained by study or from books and instruction; particularly, learning in literature, history, antiquities, and languages, as distinct from knowledge of the mathematical and physical sciences.
The act of instructing; the result of thorough instruction; the state of being erudite or learned; the acquisitions gained by extensive reading or study; particularly, learning in literature or criticism, as distinct from the sciences; scholarship.
Profound knowledge, especially that based on learning and scholarship. verb
From Latin eruditio&nbsp;("an instructing, learning, erudition"), from erudire&nbsp;("to instruct, educate, cultivate", literally "free from rudeness"), from e&nbsp;("out") + rudis&nbsp;("rude").The word "erudition" comes from the Latin eruditio, meaning "learning," which is a noun from the verb erudire, meaning "to instruct" or "to educate". This Latin verb is a compound of e- ("out") and rudis ("rude," "unskilled," or "rough"), so erudire literally meant "to free from rudeness". Therefore, erudition is the result of being "taken out of a rough or uncultivated state" through a process of education and learning.&nbsp;
Latin roots: erudire = e- ("out") + rudis ("rough," "unskilled").
Literal meaning: "To free from rudeness" or "to remove coarseness".
Figurative meaning: The process of educating or instructing someone, leading them from a state of being "rough" or unlearned to one of polished and extensive knowledge.
Modern usage: The noun "erudition" refers to the deep, scholarly knowledge that results from this process.
]]></description><link>words/erudition.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">words/erudition.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 10:18:19 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>